<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Moneydance on technocracy</title><link>https://www.ericsimmerman.com/tags/moneydance/</link><description>Recent content in Moneydance on technocracy</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 13 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.ericsimmerman.com/tags/moneydance/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Import GnuCash data into MoneyDance</title><link>https://www.ericsimmerman.com/blog/2010/06/13/import-gnucash-data-into-moneydance/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.ericsimmerman.com/blog/2010/06/13/import-gnucash-data-into-moneydance/</guid><description>&lt;div class='post'&gt;
&lt;a href="http://www.gnucash.org/"&gt;GnuCash&lt;/a&gt; served me well while I was running Ubuntu as my primary desktop but since moving to a Mac Pro I've been disappointed in the performance and non-native nature of the GnuCash Mac port. I decided to migrate to &lt;a href="http://moneydance.com/"&gt;MoneyDance&lt;/a&gt; and was quickly dismayed to discover GnuCash's poor support for standards based exporting.This GnuCash wiki-entry &lt;a href="http://wiki.gnucash.org/wiki/FAQ#Q:_How_can_I_export_data.3F"&gt;describes a few convoluted approaches to data export&lt;/a&gt; but the items it references are hopelessly outdated and generally do not function for the latest stable release - reason enough to ditch GnuCash.MoneyDance hadn't solved the problem on their end either but their wiki does &lt;a href="http://moneydance.com/trac/wiki/Frequently_Asked_Questions#CanIimportmyGnuCashdata"&gt;reference a Perl script that converts the deprecated GnuCash Postgre storage format into a MoneyDance XML file&lt;/a&gt;. Since I knew that the development release of GnuCash supports a SQLite storage format I decided to see if I could update Sid Reed's aforementioned script for this new SQLite container.I'm no Perl Monger, but &lt;a href="http://xkcd.com/208/"&gt;I do know regular expressions&lt;/a&gt;. My updated script worked well for me and seamlessly converted several years of GnuCash data. Please read the pre-requisites section in the header of this&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://www.ericsimmerman.com/wp-content/uploads/2010/06/GnuCash-MoneyDance-Importer.zip"&gt;GnuCash to MoneyDance Migration Script&lt;/a&gt; before attempting to run it. In addition to the linked zip archive, &lt;a href="http://github.com/ets/MoneyDance-GnuCash-Importer"&gt;this script is also available on github&lt;/a&gt;. Enjoy!&lt;/div&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>