<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Snowleopard on technocracy</title><link>https://www.ericsimmerman.com/tags/snowleopard/</link><description>Recent content in Snowleopard on technocracy</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2010 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.ericsimmerman.com/tags/snowleopard/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Eclipse Galileo unable to read Subversion repository</title><link>https://www.ericsimmerman.com/blog/2010/01/18/eclipse-galileo-unable-to-read-subversion-repository/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.ericsimmerman.com/blog/2010/01/18/eclipse-galileo-unable-to-read-subversion-repository/</guid><description>&lt;div class='post'&gt;
After a clean Snow Leopard install on a new machine, I fired up a fresh Galileo Eclipse and pointed it at a copy of my old workspace.&amp;nbsp; I first encountered and resolved the missing Mac OS X JRE issue described in my last post, only to then find that my existing subversion repositories were inaccessible in the new Eclipse install. I hopefully added "-clean" as the first parameter of my eclipse.ini file and restarted but the situation remained unchanged. Undeterred, I launched eclipse from the command line with a -clean startup parameter and this did the trick:/Applications/&amp;lt;your install dir/Eclipse.app/Contents/MacOS/eclipse -clean&lt;/div&gt;</description></item><item><title>Missing MacOS X VM in Eclipse Galileo on Snow Leopard</title><link>https://www.ericsimmerman.com/blog/2010/01/18/missing-macos-x-vm-in-eclipse-galileo-on-snow-leopard/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.ericsimmerman.com/blog/2010/01/18/missing-macos-x-vm-in-eclipse-galileo-on-snow-leopard/</guid><description>&lt;div class='post'&gt;
I recently encountered an issue where I was unable to add a JVM to my Eclipse install on Snow Leopard. There was no MacOS X VM option under Installed JREs -&amp;gt; Add and attempting to use the Standard VM resulted in an error. After digging around in Eclipse bug reports, I discovered this is a known issue with the Cocoa build of Galileo with PDT pre-installed.&amp;nbsp; The easy fix is to install Eclipse without PDT (just install the Eclipse IDE for Java - Cocoa 64 bit) and add PDT plugin later. When you take this route, the MacOS X VM will be configured automagically.&lt;/div&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>